<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!DOCTYPE introduction PUBLIC "-//ES//DTD book DTD version 5.5.0//EN//XML" "https://www.elsevier.com/__data/assets/text_file/0008/275669/bk55_book550_dtd.txt"><introduction docsubtype="itr" id="itr00022" version="5.5" xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://www.elsevier.com/xml/bk/dtd" xmlns:ce="http://www.elsevier.com/xml/common/dtd" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><info><ce:pii>B978-0-323-55229-5.00022-X</ce:pii><ce:doi>10.1016/B978-0-323-55229-5.00022-X</ce:doi><ce:isbn>978-0-323-55229-5</ce:isbn><ce:copyright type="full-transfer" year="2019">Elsevier Inc.</ce:copyright></info><ce:title id="tit0010">Introduction</ce:title><ce:sections><ce:para id="p0010">This section begins with an overview of the objectives of epidemiology, some of the approaches used in epidemiology, and examples of the applications of epidemiology to human health problems (<ce:intra-ref id="ii0010" xlink:href="pii:B978-0-323-55229-5.00001-2#c00001">Chapter 1</ce:intra-ref>). It then discusses how diseases are transmitted (<ce:intra-ref id="ii0015" xlink:href="pii:B978-0-323-55229-5.00002-4#c00002">Chapter 2</ce:intra-ref>). Diseases do not arise in a vacuum; they result from an interaction of human beings with their environment, including other people. An understanding of the concepts and mechanisms underlying the transmission and acquisition of disease is critical to exploring the epidemiology of human disease and to preventing and controlling many infectious diseases.</ce:para><ce:para id="p0015">To discuss the epidemiologic concepts presented in this book, we need to develop a common language, particularly for describing and comparing morbidity and mortality. <ce:intra-ref id="ii0020" xlink:href="pii:B978-0-323-55229-5.00003-6#c00003">Chapter 3</ce:intra-ref> therefore discusses morbidity and the important role of epidemiology in disease surveillance. The chapter then presents how measures of morbidity are used in both clinical medicine and public health. <ce:intra-ref id="ii0025" xlink:href="pii:B978-0-323-55229-5.00004-8#c00004">Chapter 4</ce:intra-ref> presents the methodology and approaches for using mortality data in investigations relating to public health and clinical practice. Other issues relating to the impact of disease, including quality of life and projecting the future burden of disease, are also discussed in <ce:intra-ref id="ii0030" xlink:href="pii:B978-0-323-55229-5.00004-8#c00004">Chapter 4</ce:intra-ref>.</ce:para><ce:para id="p0020">Armed with knowledge of how to describe morbidity and mortality in quantitative terms, we then turn to the question of how to assess the quality of diagnostic and screening tests that are used to determine which people in the population have a certain disease (<ce:intra-ref id="ii0035" xlink:href="pii:B978-0-323-55229-5.00005-X#c00005">Chapter 5</ce:intra-ref>). After we identify people with the disease, we need ways to describe the natural history of disease in quantitative terms; this is essential for assessing the severity of an illness and for evaluating the possible effects on survival of new therapeutic and preventive interventions (<ce:intra-ref id="ii0040" xlink:href="pii:B978-0-323-55229-5.00006-1#c00006">Chapter 6</ce:intra-ref>).</ce:para><ce:para id="p0025">This first section, then, introduces the student to the nomenclature of epidemiology, surveillance and its ramifications for determining the health of populations, and then focuses on screening and the natural history of disease.</ce:para></ce:sections></introduction>